<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ldom.net – </title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://ldom.net/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ldom.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 04:08:03 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 04:08:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>My secret trail recipes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;OK, maybe not so secret, and maybe not so original, but here’s the breakdown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;trail-mix&quot;&gt;trail mix&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For 800g of mix (4 days at 200g per day)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dried banana: 100g &amp;gt; 300 cal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Raisin: 200g &amp;gt; 600 cal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pumpkin seeds: 50g &amp;gt; 310 cal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cajou nut: 100g &amp;gt; 630 cal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dates: 150g &amp;gt; 525 cal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Almonds: 80g &amp;gt; 530 cal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Peanuts (unsalted): 120g &amp;gt; 770 cal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Total calories: 3,665 calories (approx. 460 cal/100g)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Peanuts have the best calories/weight ratio but I get bored of them pretty quickly so I don’t put that much in this mix.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fruits are great but they roughly have half the calories per weight as nuts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On multi-day hikes, I take 200g per day of this mix, plus 2 snack bars for each day (small Snickers bars, Cliff, Kind or Kind Fruit bars).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;other-meals&quot;&gt;other meals&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we’re talking about trail food, here is what I take for the other meals:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For breakfast, I mix 50g of oatmeal with 35g of hot chocolate powder and 60g of muesli. I soak it in water for 1/2hr and that gives me 540 calories for a weight of 145g.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For lunch and diner, I used to have couscous (cold soaked) and 2 small dry sausages for 520 calories and 140g or cold soaked mashed potatoes and 2 slices of dried bacon for 620 cal and 185g. Now that I’m vegetarian, I’m going to have to find something to replace the sausages and bacon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In total, it is around 2,500 cal and 700g per day of food (not counting the few snack bars).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I quickly get bored with eating the same thing every day, I tend to eat less each day on the trail, so I think from now on, I’ll go with 600g per day. I have reserves if you see what I mean and it’s not over 4 to 8 days of hiking that I’m going to develop health problems if I don’t eat enough calories per day. On a long thru-hike I would do differently of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;cold-soak-vs-warm-food&quot;&gt;cold-soak vs warm food&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I have to carry food on my back, I prefer to take less weight so I don’t take a stove or cooking utensils. I only take food that I can cold-soak in water (dry mashed potatoes, couscous or ramen). To prepare it, I have a used ice-cream container with a screwed lid. Just put the food, add water, shake well and let it soak for half an hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I’m on a canoe or a motorcycle, then things are different, I take my little gas stove and I enjoy warm food (mostly pasta and ramen).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://ldom.net/my-trail-recipes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ldom.net/my-trail-recipes/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why I cancelled my Amazon Prime subscription</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We all know the Amazon marketplace and its features. It’s a fantastic machine for selling products online, probably the best in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One-click shopping, wish lists, save for later, the infinite selection of products and vendors, the best prices for most products, etc. With Prime you get all of this, plus free shipping on almost every item.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is partially the reason why I cancelled my Prime subscription and why I’m not buying anymore from Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By not buying anymore from them, I buy a lot &lt;strong&gt;less stuff that I don’t really need&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, I’m trying to &lt;strong&gt;buy less from online sources&lt;/strong&gt;. Buying online is great and convenient, but it’s not really good for the planet to have all these small packets shipped in all directions. It’s also not good for the local shops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another reason is the &lt;strong&gt;dominant position of Amazon over online shopping&lt;/strong&gt;. Having such a big player killing all the competition is never good in the long run for consumers. There are already a lot of products that are difficult to find outside of Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally there’s the &lt;strong&gt;appalling lack of social responsibility&lt;/strong&gt; of the company. From under-paying their employees, treating them like shit in fulfilment centres, uber-izing the delivery process or even organising this ridiculous global auction for HQ2. Why would you want to participate to this? If you want to know what social responsibility is, just look at what &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patagonia.com/actionworks&quot;&gt;Patagonia&lt;/a&gt; does.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://ldom.net/why-i-cancelled-my-prime/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ldom.net/why-i-cancelled-my-prime/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to use a CI (CodeShip) to deploy a theme that won't build on Github pages</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Github pages is a nice and free way to host a web site with static pages. It also supports &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; themes, which is great when you want to make things easier to edit and post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Github pages has a bunch of themes ready to be used and they also support any Jekyll theme hosted on a public repository on github.com. You just have to use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;remote_theme&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;theme&lt;/code&gt; in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;__config.yml&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, sometimes the theme that you have chosen builds without errors locally but doesn’t build when Github tries to do it. And then the error message is everything but helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Locally you get this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;bundle &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;exec &lt;/span&gt;jekyll doctor &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--config&lt;/span&gt; _config.yml
Configuration file: _config.yml
  Your &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;test &lt;/span&gt;results are &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; Everything looks fine.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when Github builds it, you get this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;The page build failed &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for &lt;/span&gt;the master branch with the following error:

Page build failed. For more information, see https://help.github.com/en/articles/troubleshooting-github-pages-builds.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Page build failed.&lt;/code&gt; is not very useful. After hours trying to find the potential errors that they mention in the troubleshooting page, I gave up and went for a different solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution is to use a second repository (in my case: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ldom-src&lt;/code&gt;) to host the source files with the theme. These are the files you were putting on the original repository for the github pages (in my case: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ldom&lt;/code&gt;). Then setup a CI server (Continuous Integration) to build the static files every time you push to the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-src&lt;/code&gt; repository and push the static file to the github pages repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, you can put together the CI server yourself, using Jenkins for example, but it’s easier when you don’t have to manage a server for that. CodeShip is a CI service (I have no affiliation with them) that offers a free account limited to 100 builds per month (which is plenty for a personal site that you’ll update 30 times max per month).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is how you set it up and the scripts to use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://codeship.com&quot;&gt;https://codeship.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sign up for the free tier.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a new project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Setup Commands tab, select “I want to create my own custom commands” and use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;bundle &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;install
&lt;/span&gt;bundle &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;exec &lt;/span&gt;jekyll build &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--config&lt;/span&gt; _config.yml
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Setup Commands text area, use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-shell&quot; data-lang=&quot;shell&quot;&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8
9
10
11
12
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;REMOTE_REPOSITORY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;${&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;REMOTE_REPOSITORY&lt;/span&gt;:?&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'You need to configure the REMOTE_REPOSITORY environment variable!'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;REMOTE_BRANCH&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;${&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;REMOTE_BRANCH&lt;/span&gt;:?&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'You need to configure the REMOTE_BRANCH environment variable!'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;set&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-e&lt;/span&gt;
git config &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--global&lt;/span&gt; user.email &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&amp;lt;your email&amp;gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
git config &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--global&lt;/span&gt; user.name &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&amp;lt;your name&amp;gt; (codeship)&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
git clone &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;${&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;REMOTE_REPOSITORY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; _tmp &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-b&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;${&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;REMOTE_BRANCH&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cp&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-R&lt;/span&gt; _site/&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; _tmp/
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cd &lt;/span&gt;_tmp
git add &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
git status
git commit &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-m&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;new build&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
git push origin master
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Environment tab, create 2 environment variables (to be used in the script above):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;REMOTE_REPOSITORY&lt;/code&gt;: put the address of the destination repository, the one for the static Github pages, eg. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git@github.com:ldom/ldom.git&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;REMOTE_BRANCH&lt;/code&gt;: put &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;master&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The last step is to configure CodeShip and Github to allow the deploy script to push (write) to the destination repository.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is described on this page: &lt;a href=&quot;https://documentation.codeship.com/basic/builds-and-configuration/access-to-other-repositories/#sts=The%20Machine%20User%20Solution&quot;&gt;https://documentation.codeship.com/basic/builds-and-configuration/access-to-other-repositories/#sts=The%20Machine%20User%20Solution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recommend using the “Machine User” solution. 
It involves:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;creating a new github.com user and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;give it access to the destination repository (by inviting it as a collaborator in the destination repository),&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;then you have to remove the key from the Deploy section under the destination repository (not your user settings, but the repository settings).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At last, you need to put that key (that has to be copied from General tab of the Project Settings in CodeShip) as a new key on the “Machine User” github account. (Note that if you don’t remove it first from the Deploy settings of the destination repository, you won’t be able to add that key to the “Machine User” keys).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once all of this is done, you’ll enjoy a full automated (and free) system where you just have to push to the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-src&lt;/code&gt; repository for everything to be built and deployed to Github pages!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://ldom.net/ci-for-github-pages/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ldom.net/ci-for-github-pages/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
